Trista Crossen

A recent graduate of BSA in Software Development from WGU

Profile

I graduated from Western Governors University in October 2023 with a BSA in Software

Projects

Undergraduate Capstone

Created a business plan for a hypothetical international financial coaching firm to update its current appointment tracking software using the cumulative knowledge gathered during the software development program. I used my Software 2 project as a base and added search functionality, inheritance, and polymorphism, and made the application secure against SQL injection attacks.

Mobile Application

Created a mobile application using Android Studio, Java, and SQL to help hypothetical college students keep better track of their classes and assessments. The application can send notifications for assessments, as well as send notes via email and SMS messaging.

Software 2 Advanced Java Concepts

Created a stand-alone PC application using IntelliJ IDEA, Java, and SQL to help a hypothetical company keep track of customers and appointments. The application connects to a database and can read and write to the database. It also lets users know if they have an upcoming appointment when they log in. The application log-in screen text reads as either English or French depending on the language settings of the user's machine.

Advanced-Data Management

Created a business plan for a hypothetical DVD rental business to run business reports using SQL and database management software to help increase revenue. These reports pulled data from different tables in the database to gather information suited for the client.

Software 1

Created a stand-alone PC application using IntelliJ IDEA and Java to help a hypothetical shop update its inventory management system. The application can add, update, delete, and search parts and other inventory in the shop's warehouse.

User Experience Design

Created a business plan to create a navigable prototype of a hypothetical website for a travel agency. This business plan focused on meeting user experience guidelines, taking the user testing data, and implementing changes where appropriate while still meeting business requirements.

User Interface Design

Created a business plan to create a navigable prototype of a hypothetical website for a veterinary practice. The prototype was created using PowerPoint. The business plan focused on what kind of users would be likely to use the website and how the updated site could better serve their needs.

Work Experience

Customer Service Representative

TTec

10/2019 - 01/2020

Customer Service rep for United Healthcare

Responsibilities:

- Taking calls from customers.
- Using the company intranet and software programs to answer customer questions.
- Helping the customers get in contact with/set up appointments with care providers.
- Documenting customer complaints.

Independent Cleaning Contractor

Self-employed

01/2012 - 10/2019

Self-employed cleaner for residential and commercial properties

Responsibilities:

Scheduling clients.

- Performing cleaning duties per client directions.
- Invoicing clients for services rendered.

Laundry tech

Heritage Living Center

05/2010 - 12/2011

Laundry and other environmental services in a nursing home setting

Responsibilities:

- Sorting linens and personal clothing items before washing.
- Loading the washing machines and starting the wash cycle appropriate for the load.
- Moving damp clothes from the washers to the driers.
- Folding linens and hanging personal items for return.
- Delivering personal items to resident rooms, and linens to the shared hallway linen closets for use by staff.

Education

Western Governors University

Bachelor of Science: Software Development, March 2020 - October 2023

Graduated in 3 and a half years with a 3.0 GPA.

CompTIA Project+

Certificate earned December 2020

Axelos ITIL4 Foundation Cert

Certificate earned October 2021